<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>datacubeR on datacubeR</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in datacubeR on datacubeR</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This is just mine. Use it giving proper credit.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propuesta Redes Convolucionales</title>
      <link>/project/convolutional-nets-sp/memoria-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/convolutional-nets-sp/memoria-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#redes-convolucionales&#34;&gt;Redes Convolucionales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#como-se-relaciona-esto-con-las-redes-convolucionales&#34;&gt;¿Cómo se relaciona esto con las Redes Convolucionales?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#como-se-va-especializando-la-red-para-ser-cada-vez-mas-detallista&#34;&gt;¿Cómo se va especializando la red para ser cada vez más detallista?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#como-se-relaciona-este-problema-con-estructuras&#34;&gt;¿Cómo se relaciona este problema con Estructuras?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#el-paper-de-finol&#34;&gt;El Paper de Finol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#solucion&#34;&gt;Solución&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#puntos-interesantes-para-la-investigacion.&#34;&gt;Puntos Interesantes para la Investigación.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#era-sugerencia-quizas-no-para-la-memoria-pero-para-seguir-investigando&#34;&gt;1era Sugerencia (Quizás no para la Memoria, pero para seguir investigando)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#da-sugerencia&#34;&gt;2da Sugerencia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#era-sugerencia.&#34;&gt;3era Sugerencia.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ta-sugerencia-crear-imagenes-estructurales&#34;&gt;4ta Sugerencia “Crear Imágenes Estructurales”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;redes-convolucionales&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Redes Convolucionales&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las redes convolucionales es un tipo de Red que esta especializada principalmente en extraer características de imágenes. Si bien es cierto es posible utilizar Redes convolucionales para otras aplicaciones, el análisis de imágenes y la Visión Computacional son la especialidad de estas redes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Principal ventaja sobre una Red neural normal es que no está densamente conectada. Sino que selecciona cuidadosamente las neuronas a las que se conectará cambiando la operación matricial de Producto Punto por una convolución.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La definición formal de Convolución es:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ (f * g)(x)= \int_{-\infty}^{\infty}{f(\eta)\cdot g(x-\eta) d\eta} \]&lt;/span&gt; La interpretación más clásica de esta integral corresponde al producto de funciones al desplazar una por sobre la otra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;como-se-relaciona-esto-con-las-redes-convolucionales&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;¿Cómo se relaciona esto con las Redes Convolucionales?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El análisis de Imágenes es bastante complicado. La manera en la que un computador es capaz de ver una imágen es parseando e interpretandola por un Tensor de Pixeles. Dependiendo de la resolución dela Imagen este Tensor será cada vez más grande, por lo tanto usar Redes Densas supone un gran costo computacional por todos los $ w_{i,j}$ que será necesario calcular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normalmente el análisis de Imágenes utiliza tensor de este estilo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/4D_Tensor.png&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs1}Estructura de Tensores de Imágenes&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Estructura de Tensores de Imágenes
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Matriz de Pixeles de Dimensiones Alto x Ancho más una Pofundidad de Canales RGB que dan el color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es por esto que las redes convolucionales ocupan esta operación para reconocer patrones específicos dentro del Tensor de Imagen. La manera en que está convolución se lleva a cabo es por medio de un Filtro. Este filtro es otro Tensor que posee generalmente dimensiones de 3x3 o 5x5 el cual se desplaza a través del tensor de imágenes para construir un Mapa de Características.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://saama-dbe0.kxcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/01.jpg?iv=124&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Invisible.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs2}Aplicación de un Filtro en redes Convolucionales&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Aplicación de un Filtro en redes Convolucionales
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://ufldl.stanford.edu/tutorial/images/Convolution_schematic.gif&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normalmente luego de la Aplicación del Filtro el Mapa de Características es pasado por una ReLU lo que genera que se realcen ciertos atributos de la imagen lo que permite que la red aprenda a diferenciar características específicas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependiendo del filtro aplicado, se verán ciertos atributos de la imagen o no. Cabe destacar que los filtros parten como números aleatorios que se van entrenando en los distintos Pasos de la red (Forward and Backward).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si intentamos analizar la foto de un gato, luego de aplicar filtros, esto es lo que un computador comienza a ver:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs3&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Cat.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs3}Feature Map&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: Feature Map
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs4&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Cat_Filters.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs4}Resultado del Entrenamiento de Filtros&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 4: Resultado del Entrenamiento de Filtros
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;como-se-va-especializando-la-red-para-ser-cada-vez-mas-detallista&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;¿Cómo se va especializando la red para ser cada vez más detallista?&lt;/h2&gt;
Luego de la red Convolucional hay una reducción de Dimensionalidad, para llevarse acabo se utiliza una Capa de pooling, esta puede ser una Average Pooling o Max Pooling (generalmente ésta última es la más utilizada) la cual reduce la dimensión del problema para luego aplicar una nueva Capa de Red convolucional pero con más filtros que el paso anterior.
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*vbfPq-HvBCkAcZhiSTZybg.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs5&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Invisible.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs5}Max Pooling&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 5: Max Pooling
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Una vez que se ha llegado al nivel de espacialización deseado, se llevan todas las caracterícticas a un vector que es pasado por una capa densamente conectada para entregar los outputs correspondientes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Una Configuración típica podría verse así:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs6&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Car_Convnet.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs6}Especialización de la Red&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 6: Especialización de la Red
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;como-se-relaciona-este-problema-con-estructuras&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;¿Cómo se relaciona este problema con Estructuras?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No tiene relación alguna. Porque este tipo de redes fue diseñada para el desarrollo del análisis de imágenes. Además es la manera más intuitiva de analizar el funcionamiento de estas redes. Las dos principales caracerísticas de las Redes Convolucionales son:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La extracción de Características&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translation/Shift Invariance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esto quiere decir que la red se especializa en detectar Patrones que no dependen de su posición ni que deben ser identicos para ser detectados. Por ejemplo una oreja de gato se detectara si es grande, si es pequeña, si es de otro color si esta rotada o desplazada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Son estas características las que permitirían desarrollar otro tipo de problemas si es que pueden ser planteadas como un tensor de imágen o similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;el-paper-de-finol&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;El Paper de Finol&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Paper propone solucionar un problema cualquiera de estructuras usando redes Convolucionales. Lo que ellos primeramente plantean es la obtención de Valores propios para un material de propiedades variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para ello se utiliza una barra dividida en 100 Elementos en las que se miden dos Propiedades, el Módulo de Elasticidad E y la Densidad $ $ .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En simple lo que se está planteando es una red convolucional para analizar una Imagen de 1 Pixel de Alto por 100 de Ancho, donde los Canales que representan color, en este caso representan propiedades físicas del Elemento. Dada las propiedades de la imagen esto puede extrapolarse a que las Redes convolucionales pueden analizar Data Secuencial, en este caso cada Elemento de la Barra están en secuencia debido a la continuidad del la barra. Aunque cabe destacar que la red Convolucional no se deja llevar por el orden ya que sus patrones no dependen de la posición.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mi Supuesto&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esto podría traducirse en que los invesigadores pensaron en quizás un elemento equivalente de un Modulo $ E_{eq} $ en serie dado que es una barra unidimensional y el orden de los $ E_{i} $ y $ _{i} $ no influyen en la propiedad equivalente final del elemento.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Además el problema que se está resolviendo es de valores propios, no hay elementos externos que indiquen que el orden de las propiedades mecánicas influyan en el cálculo final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bajo estas características es que el uso de la Red Convolucional es válida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;solucion&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solución&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para resolver el problema de Valores propios para un Cristal dividido en 100 Elementos se utiliza la siguiente configuración:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs7&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Finol_Net.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs7}Solución de Finol&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 7: Solución de Finol
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Se utiliza una Red Secuencial aplicando un Filtro de Largo 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al no utilizar padding el vector se reduce a 98 x 1 x 275 donde 275 corresponde teóricamente al número de filtros que está utilizando. Esto no sale definido en el Paper y es algo que averigué investigando por mi parte.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Se utiliza una segunda capa convolucional. La razón de esto no lo sé. Normalmente no he visto casos de dos Capas convolucionales seguidas excepto en modelos muy avanzados.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Se utiliza una capa Max Pooling para reducir de largo 2 que disminuye el tamaño de la red a la mitad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luego de esto se une con una Red Convencional densamente conectada. Lo que normalmente he visto es que se usa una flatten Layer que aplana la reducción de dimensiones que se ha dado hasta ahora. El valor esperado debería ser de 275 x 48, pero no sé porque ocupa 500 nodos. *Se utilizan 3 capas ocultas para luego generar una capa de 20 unidades de salida por los 20 valores propios esperados para el problema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;puntos-interesantes-para-la-investigacion.&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Puntos Interesantes para la Investigación.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Estoy tomando un curso en Datacamp y uno público de Stanford acerca del uso de redes Convolucionales. Dentro del curso se dan varias recomendaciones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Para un problema de imágenes de 64 x 64 x 3 para predecir si hay un gato en la imágen o no se requieren aproximadamente 10.000 imágenes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Se recomienda usar la mínima resolución posible para distinguir a nivel humano de tal manera de bajar el poder computacional que requiere la red.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A mayor resolución más imágenes. Menor Resolución menos Imágenes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cualquier Matriz puede ser interpretada como una imágen. En la cual una Red Convolucional puede encontrar patrones. Por lo que perfectamente la matriz de rigidez puede ser tratado como una imagen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs8&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/matrix_image.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs8}Transformación de Matriz en Imágen&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 8: Transformación de Matriz en Imágen
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Las redes convolucionales poseen propiedades de Memoria dado que su principal función es la Extracción de Características. Existen modelos pre-entrenados de redes que Pueden usarse para perfeccionar otras tareas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Un ejemplo que leí fue una red que fue pre-entrenada con imágenes de muebles pero que luego se adaptó para mejor la identificación de animales. La red a pesar de no ser entrenada con animales, era capaz de reconocer bordes y características muy finas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;era-sugerencia-quizas-no-para-la-memoria-pero-para-seguir-investigando&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1era Sugerencia (Quizás no para la Memoria, pero para seguir investigando)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uso de Redes convolucionales para calcular Inversas de la Matriz de Rigidez. Siendo este el proceso más caro de la resolución de estructuras quizás podría realizarse el desarrollo de una Red Pre-entrenada que sea capaz de calcular Inversas de Muchas Matrices de tal Manera de agilizar el proceso más caro de la resolución de estructuras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;da-sugerencia&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2da Sugerencia&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si bien las redes Convolucionales pueden dar buenos resultados para data secuencial, dada su caracteristica de &lt;em&gt;“Invariante a la Traslación”&lt;/em&gt;, puede encontrar patrones incorrectos cuando el orden sí importa. Se desaconseja su uso en series de tiempo, ya que el orden de la información importa al momento de predecir. Para contrarestar esto, se agrega una capa de redes recurrentes (RNN) que ayuda a establecer la secuencia como un prerequisito del análisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Es posible realizar modelos paralelos en la que se ingrese data distinta como input de la Red. Por ejemplo la Matriz de Rigidez del problema como &lt;em&gt;“imagen”&lt;/em&gt; y los Propiedades Mecánicas como vector o hasta las Cargas a las que está sometida la estructura como vector, de esa manera todos los elementos son parte de los Input del problema para predecir de manera más acertada los desplazamientos normales o umbrales del problema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;era-sugerencia.&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3era Sugerencia.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generar una red no secuencial considerando todos los inputs del problema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dado que el análisis de las Imágenes poseen una característica Espacial y secuencial me da la impresión que se puede trabajar en optimizaciones al proceso de Condensación de Grados de Libertad. Sería posible que la red redujera problemas con gran cantidad de grados de libertad en Rigideces equivalentes que pueden ser planteadas como una imágen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Así mismo dado que también posee propiedades de Profundidad podría ayudar al desarrollo de analisis de estructuras en 3 dimensiones que es algo que yo no recuerdo haber visto si no era usando algo como ETABS o SAP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me da la impresión de que Redes Convolucionales pueden ayudar al desarrollo de Propiedades equivalentes usando su característica secuencial para propiedades en serie y su profundidad como propiedades en paralelo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ta-sugerencia-crear-imagenes-estructurales&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4ta Sugerencia “Crear Imágenes Estructurales”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizar la estructura de la matriz de Rigidez con 3 Canales simulando el RGB: Rigidez, Cargas en Eje X y Cargas en Eje Y. Habría que buscar una manera de modelar dentro de la matriz los apoyos, que normalmente no son considerados dentro de la Matriz a priori.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para un Enrejado de 9 Elementos esto sería una Imágen de 9 x 9 x 3, lo cual no supondría una gran cantidad de casos para entrenar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation Functions</title>
      <link>/project/activation-functions/activation-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/activation-functions/activation-functions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#activation-functions&#34;&gt;Activation Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#identity&#34;&gt;Identity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-function&#34;&gt;Step Function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#linear-function&#34;&gt;Linear Function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#sigmoid-function&#34;&gt;Sigmoid Function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#hyperbolic-tangent&#34;&gt;Hyperbolic Tangent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#relu&#34;&gt;ReLU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#leaky-relu&#34;&gt;Leaky ReLU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#softmax&#34;&gt;Softmax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-to-choose-the-perfect-activation-function&#34;&gt;How to choose the perfect Activation function?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;activation-functions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Activation Functions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation functions are one of the most important characteristic of ANN. They basically decide whether a neuron should be activated or not. When a particular threshold is reached the Neuron will fire, meaning they will transmit the input signal to the next layer of the Network. Another Important feature of Activation Functions is that some of them provide the non-linearity. This is particular important because Activation functions help expand the range of problems that the Neural Networks can address. Finally Activation functions will play a major role when optimizing the edges weights when Backpropagation Algorithm comes into play, depending of their derivatives values is how the Gradient will change helping to decrease the error associated the Network prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these Activation Functions are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;identity&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the most basic Activation, basically, do not alter the Neuron at all. The problem with this type of activation function is that is linear, transforming the Network into a Linear Regression limiting its classification capabilities for non-linear phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-function&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Step Function&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The binary function is extremely simple. It returns 1 if certain threshold is reached or 0 otherwise. The main drawback of this function is that his derivative is 0, meaning it is not useful in the optimizing process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function is defined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ f(x)= \left\{ \begin{array}{lcc}
             0 &amp;amp;   if  &amp;amp; x &amp;lt; 0 \\
             \\ 1 &amp;amp;  if  &amp;amp; x \geq 0 
             \end{array}
   \right. \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Step.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs}Step Function&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Step Function
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;linear-function&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Linear Function&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another option, being the main difference the existence of a slope. In this case the derivative will be constant, which can be problematic because when trying to decrease the error no matter how right or off you are the gradient will be the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function goes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ f(x) = a x \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Linear.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs2}Linear Function&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Linear Function
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;sigmoid-function&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sigmoid Function&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very popular activation function. The main advantages of this function is that it is smooth, S-shaped, it is continuously differentiable and non-linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function is defined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ f(x)= \frac{1}{1+e^{-x}} \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs3&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Sigmoid.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs3}Sigmoid Function&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: Sigmoid Function
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The derivative of this function is always positive and greater than 0 and x-dependent so it is very helpful when optimizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the setbacks is that only ranges from 0 to 1, for one thing is very limiting with the output but for the other it is particularly useful when dealing with probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;hyperbolic-tangent&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hyperbolic Tangent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperbolic Tangent or $ tanh(x) $ is just an scaled version of the Sigmoid function. It is defined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ tanh(x)= 2 \cdot sigmoid(2x) - 1 = \frac{2}{1+e^{-2x}} - 1 \]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs4&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Tanh.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs4}Hyperbolic Tangent Function&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 4: Hyperbolic Tangent Function
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ tanh $ works similarly to sigmoid but it is symmetric at the x - axis. Normally $ tanh $ and sigmoid can be used interchangeably depending on the requirements of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;relu&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ReLU&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ReLu stands for Rectified Linear unit and it is defined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ f(x)= max(0,x) \]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs5&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Relu.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs5}ReLU Function&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 5: ReLU Function
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the most used function nowadays in hidden layers. The main capability is that it doesn’t activate all of the functions creating sparsity in the network, allowing efficiency in computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This function is limited at the positive side so it is not suggested for Output Layers. Another drawback is that not activated neurons in the range $ x &amp;lt; 0 $ will not be optimized since derivative is zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;leaky-relu&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Leaky ReLU&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an improved version of the ReLU function. It is not widely used yet and it has a subtle difference with ReLu: &lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ f(x)= \left\{ \begin{array}{lcc}
             ax &amp;amp;   if  &amp;amp; x &amp;lt; 0 \\
             \\ x &amp;amp;  if  &amp;amp; x \geq 0 
             \end{array}
   \right. \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs6&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Leaky.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs6}Leaky ReLU Function&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 6: Leaky ReLU Function
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This solves the problem of dead neurons during Optimization process, since the derivative of $ x &amp;lt; 0 $ is not zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;softmax&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Softmax&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sigmoid kind-of function capable of handling more than 2 classes. The function is defined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ \sigma(z)_{j}=\frac{e^{z_{j}}}{\sum_{k=1}^{K}e^{z_{k}}} \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The softmax functions are normally used in output layers when trying to solve classification problems with more than 2 classes..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-to-choose-the-perfect-activation-function&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How to choose the perfect Activation function?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there is not a clear answer to this, but definitely some guidelines we can follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sigmoid functions generally work better in classification problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sigmoids and tanh functions are sometimes avoided due to the &lt;em&gt;vanishing gradient problem&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReLU function is a general activation function and is used in most cases these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we encounter a case of dead neurons in our networks the leaky ReLU function is the best choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always keep in mind that ReLU function should only be used in the hidden layers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a rule of thumb, you can begin with using ReLU function and then move over to other activation functions in case ReLU doesn’t provide with optimum results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manning.com/books/deep-learning-with-r&#34;&gt;Deep Learning with R&lt;/a&gt; provides some other Guidelines to use Activation Functions in the Output Layer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary Classification: &lt;strong&gt;Sigmoid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiclass Single-Label Classification: &lt;strong&gt;Softmax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiclass Multi-Label Classification: &lt;strong&gt;Sigmoid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression to Arbitrary Values: &lt;strong&gt;Identity&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;None&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression to Values between 0 to 1: &lt;strong&gt;Sigmoid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Neural Networks</title>
      <link>/project/neural-nets-101/intro-to-nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/neural-nets-101/intro-to-nn/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-an-artificial-neural-network&#34;&gt;What is an Artificial Neural Network?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#basic-structure&#34;&gt;Basic Structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-problems-can-neural-networks-solve&#34;&gt;What Problems can Neural Networks solve?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#classification&#34;&gt;Classification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#regression&#34;&gt;Regression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#typical-problems-solved-with-neural-networks&#34;&gt;Typical Problems solved with Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;what-is-an-artificial-neural-network&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is an Artificial Neural Network?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Picture you see up there is far a way from what a real Neural Network looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually it is more similar to something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/ANN.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs}Multi-Layer Perceptron&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Multi-Layer Perceptron
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration showed above is nothing but a visual representation of serial Matrix Multiplications. The neural network (aka ANN that stands for Artificial Neural Networks) itself is not an algorithm, but rather a framework for many different machine learning algorithms to work together and process complex data inputs&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANN are inspired by Neurons but they work in a completely different fashion. The main advantage of this system is that organizes successive Matrix multiplications and provides a visual representation of the different steps in the Optimization algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different types of Networks, Densely Connected, Convolutional, Recurrent, Long Short Memory, Radial Biased, Autoencoders, and so on. All of them having their own area of specialization, strengths and shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;basic-structure&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Basic Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Network will contain Nodes/Units, emulating Neurons and Edges, emulating the connection between Units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally the Units are organized by Layers, every Network should contain a first layer for Inputs, a last Layer for Outputs and Intermediate Layers, also known as Hidden Layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Basic_ANN.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs2}Basic Neural Network&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Basic Neural Network
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Input Nodes $ i_{j} $ will contain Input Values to train the Network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edges will provide weights $ w_{j} $.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hidden Layer Nodes $ h_{j} $ will contain the result of Sum Product between Input Nodes and weighted edges connected to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally Output Nodes $ o_{j} $ will contain the result of Sum Product between hidden Nodes and the Edges Connected to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optionally, Networks can include a Bias $ b_{j} $ to control values of the network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Network then will calculate values in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ h_{1} = w_{1} i_{1} + w_{2} i_{2} + b_{1} = 0.15 \cdot 0.05 + 0.25 \cdot 0.10 + 0.35 = 0.3825 \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ h_{2} = w_{2} i_{1} + w_{4} i_{2} + b_{1} = 0.20 \cdot 0.05 + 0.30 \cdot 0.10 + 0.35 = 0.39 \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ o_{1} = w_{5} h_{1} + w_{7} h_{2} + b_{2} = 0.40 \cdot 0.3825 + 0.50 \cdot 0.39 + 0.60 = 0.948 \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ o_{2} = w_{6} h_{1} + w_{8} h_{2} + b_{2} = 0.45 \cdot 0.3825 + 0.55 \cdot 0.39 + 0.60 = 0.986625 \]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is called a forward pass. All the Input Values were able to move through the Network by the Edge Connections up to the Output. Normally, when the Network is trained, there are expected Output values that will be compared with the ones obtained with the Forward Pass in order to compute the Error. In this case 0.01 and 0.99 respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-problems-can-neural-networks-solve&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What Problems can Neural Networks solve?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally there are two Problems that Neural Networks Solves, Classification and Regression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;classification&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Classification&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Classification problem is the most common problem addressed by Neural Networks. It implies to classify based on a Probability. The output will calculate how likely is that an specific label corresponds to a class. Classification problems can be sub-divided into other sub-types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary Classification: As the name implies, it involves two classes: Spam or not Span, Positive or Negative, Man or Woman, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiclass Classification: In this case several labels can be applied: Is it a Dog, Cat, Horse? What Car Brand is that? etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;regression&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Regression&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of problems involved calculate a number associated to a Metric. Typical Problems are predicting House Values, Temperature, Balances, Displacements, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;typical-problems-solved-with-neural-networks&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Typical Problems solved with Neural Networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neural Networks are powerful and they are the most cutting-edge methodology to make computers do the most incredibly/creepy things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we think computers can do anything like Analyzing Photos, Driving Cars, Recognizing Animals, Predicting Prices and so on, the scope of their work is completely limited to just one thing: &lt;strong&gt;Computing Tensors&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tensors are the generalization to N dimensions of Matrices. Basically any problem that can be represented by Tensors is something that Neural Networks could potentially solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different kind of Tensors can solve specific problems. Here some examples taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manning.com/books/deep-learning-with-r&#34;&gt;Deep Learning with R&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vector data—2D tensors of shape (samples, features): This is the Most common Data Structure Data Scientist uses in a daily basis. Basically a Matrix, having Features as Columns and Samples as Rows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Timeseries data or sequence data—3D tensors of shape (samples, timesteps, features): This is something a little bit fancier, having several timeseries organized as a collection of matrices, this creates a 3D Tensor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs3&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/3D_Tensor.png&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs3}Multiple Timeseries data&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: Multiple Timeseries data
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images—4D tensors of shape (samples, height, width, channels) or (samples, channels, height, width): Images are represented as Pixel Matrices, Every Pixel also has RGB Channels giving the color properties to it, thus a 3D Tensor. Adding several samples of Images to analize and you have a 4D Tensor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:figs4&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/4D_Tensor.png&#34; alt=&#34;\label{fig:figs4}Image Data&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 4: Image Data
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video—5D tensors of shape (samples, frames, height, width, channels) or (samples, frames, channels, height, width): Videos are nothing but a collection of Sequencial Images. So You’ll have different Samples of Sequencial Images producing which is a 4D Tensor, since you analize several samples of Videos, you’ll get a 5D Tensor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conclusion&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neural Networks are simple visual representations of Tensor Calcultions that are capable of addressing different real life problems. So far we have covered how the Networks transmit Information from Input to Output also called Forward Pass, but there are some other concepts that are necessary to understan in order to fully unerstand how to properly train a Neural Network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deep-learning&#34;&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I got to know Deep Learning by chance. I remember to have had a College subject called Operational Investigation Fundamentals and they taugth Artifical Intelligence algorithms. Neural networks were mentioned but I never thought I could even understand what they were about.
During my first real job (as a quasi-Engineer) I always thougth I never paid sufficient attention to that subject. The subject basically covered some optimization models and for some reason &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; was there, just sky-high level mentions in some classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I remember during my &lt;strong&gt;Data Science Program&lt;/strong&gt;, we had 3 different Research Projects (this was at my Butterflies and Unicorns time, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking, go here). One was Data Analytics to Measure Cars Price (super-duper boring), the second was Using Sentiment Analysis to Understand whether Lyrics of Top 20 Billboard were related to Decade&amp;rsquo;s Most Important Facts (I did this, and it was super interesting) and there was a third one I really tried to sneak out: Sentiment Annalysis with Machine Learning. Machine Learning sounded really scary to be my very first Data Science Project, so I put it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that a colleague just joined my team at EVS and he had this awesome Max Kuhn book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bookdepository.com/Applied-Predictive-Modeling-Max-Kuhn/9781461468486?redirected=true&amp;amp;utm_medium=Google&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Base1&amp;amp;utm_source=CL&amp;amp;utm_content=Applied-Predictive-Modeling&amp;amp;selectCurrency=CLP&amp;amp;w=AF4JAU961V0NQ9A803TP&amp;amp;pdg=pla-309526196374:kwd-309526196374:cmp-1653769863:adg-64191594660:crv-318349950654:pid-9781461468486:dev-c&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAjw-ZvlBRBbEiwANw9UWplud3A9daFx70SYI7-0t29OmknuQProNRgQtt39d572kbgsKqflBhoCwV8QAvD_BwE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Applied Predictive Modeling&lt;/a&gt;. And I thought: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m more experienced now, so probably I can take a look at this&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. And well I discovered &lt;code&gt;caret&lt;/code&gt; and completely blew my mind (But I still dislike its little to null compatibility with Tidyverse, but thanks Max Kuhn for creating &lt;code&gt;parsnip&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Nico, I think, was the first guy mentioning Deep Learning, because he created the XoR problem in VBA and also took Andrew Ng specialization Course, and
I started to feel interested in the Field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I dicovered Keras, the R API just came out (I think so) and I got this other super Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Deep-Learning-R-Francois-Chollet/dp/161729554X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Deep Learning with R&lt;/a&gt; and I just learned so much, but not enough. I think I learned a bit of Keras but I suddenly realized I had no idea about the inner black-box, so I just wanted to learn and understand what the hell is happening inside that box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well here I am&amp;hellip; Trying to understand&amp;hellip; and I didn&amp;rsquo;t do very well. Internet has little to no information about theory. Codes are everywhere, but why that code is useful is just not important for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my intent is creating content (R based obviously, because R is not popular for Deep Learning either) for me to learn, and hopefully spread the word about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the thing is I need to finish my Thesis, and my Professor told me: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why don&amp;rsquo;t you combine what you know about Deep Learning (sincerely, not too much) with Structure Engineering?&lt;/strong&gt; And you know what, this is something really unexplored in the field, so here I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully publishing my findings help to have a better understanding of what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, also i can keep track of it and help others on my way (I love teaching, so this is a good way to get started).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to have news about my Thesis soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deep-learning&#34;&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I got to know Deep Learning by chance. I remember to have had a College subject called Operation Investigation Fundamentals and they taugth Artifical Intelligence algorithms. Neural networks were mentioned but I never thought I could even understand what they were about.
During my first real job (as an engineer) I always thougth I never paid sufficient attention to that subject. The subject basically covered some optimization models and for some reason &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; was there, just sky-high level mentions in some classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I remember during my Data Science Program, we had 3 different Research Projects (this was at my Butterflies and Unicorns time, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking, go here). One was Data Analytics to Measure Cars Price (super-duper boring), the second was Using Sentiment Analysis to Understand if the Topics of Top 20 Billboard were related to Decade&amp;rsquo;s Most Important Facts (I did this, and it was super interesting) and there was a third one I really tried to sneak out: Sentiment Annalysis with Machine Learning. Machine Learning sounded really scary to be my very first Data Science Project, so I put it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that a colleague just joined my team at EVS and he had this awesome Max Kuhn book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bookdepository.com/Applied-Predictive-Modeling-Max-Kuhn/9781461468486?redirected=true&amp;amp;utm_medium=Google&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Base1&amp;amp;utm_source=CL&amp;amp;utm_content=Applied-Predictive-Modeling&amp;amp;selectCurrency=CLP&amp;amp;w=AF4JAU961V0NQ9A803TP&amp;amp;pdg=pla-309526196374:kwd-309526196374:cmp-1653769863:adg-64191594660:crv-318349950654:pid-9781461468486:dev-c&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAjw-ZvlBRBbEiwANw9UWplud3A9daFx70SYI7-0t29OmknuQProNRgQtt39d572kbgsKqflBhoCwV8QAvD_BwE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Applied Predictive Modeling&lt;/a&gt;. And I thought: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m more experienced now, so probably I can take a look at this&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. And well I discovered &lt;code&gt;caret&lt;/code&gt; and completely blew my mind (But I still dislike its little to null compatibility with Tidyverse, thanks Max Kuhn for creating Parsnip).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Nico, I think, was the first guy mentioning Deep Learning, because he created the XoR problem in VBA and also took Andrew Ng specialization, and
I started to feel interested in the Field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I dicovered Keras, the R API just came out (I think so) and I got this other super Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Deep-Learning-R-Francois-Chollet/dp/161729554X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Deep Learning with R&lt;/a&gt; and I just learned so much, but not enough. I think I learned a bit of Keras but suddenly realized I had no idea about the inner black-box, so I just wanted to learn and understand what the hell is happening inside that box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well here I am&amp;hellip; Trying to understand&amp;hellip; and I didn&amp;rsquo;t do very well, The Internet has little to no information about theory. Codes are everywhere, but why that code is useful is just not important for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my intent is creating content (R based obviously, because R is not popular for Deep Learning either) for me to learn, and hopefully spread the word about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the thing is I need to finish my Thesis, and my Professor told me why don&amp;rsquo;t we combine what you know about Deep Learning (sincerely, not too much) with Structure Engineering, and you know what this is something really unexplored in the field, so here I go. Hopefully publishing my findings help to have a better understanding of what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, also i can keep track of it, and I can help others (I love teaching, so this is a good way to get started).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to have news about my Thesis soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Project</title>
      <link>/post/my-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-thesis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-am-i-not-graduated-yet&#34;&gt;Why am I not graduated yet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduation is something we all are longing. Well, I recognize this is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been evading. The main reason is because I&amp;rsquo;m not working on what I studied. But, what the hell, I think I like Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, Long Story Short&amp;hellip; I was about to study Mathematical Engineering but I asked myself, where can I possibly work as a Mathematical Engineer ? (In my current job, obviously 😅)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decide to go for Civil Engineering because it has a decent amount of advanced Maths that was something I was looking for and a High Employment Index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I started working as a Civil Engineer in INVAR as soon as I finished my internship. I just loved it, I learned so much, but the thingwas that they didn&amp;rsquo;t pay too much. So I decided to take a position at Aguas del Valle. Sincerely, and very respectfully, it has been the worst choice of my life, not only because it was 5 hours away of my Hometown, but also because they took my soul out of my body and make me spend awful moments doing absolutely nothing. There is nothing more frustrating than doing nothing all day long in a desk in a Company you don&amp;rsquo;t feel a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the Evalueserve Post showed up. A friend referred me to the Data Science Program (DSP) and then I fell in love with Data Science. During the program I learned SQL, VBA, SAS 👍, R, Tableau and definitely built up my English and Communication skills. Felipe, help me prepare my first interview in English and thanks to him I had the English I needed to learn all I know so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upskilling and moving through cities took all of my time, besides I got married (Best Decision so far) but a lot to do, hence, no time to finish my Thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened-with-my-thesis&#34;&gt;What happened with my Thesis?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well in INVAR I worked as an Hidraulics Engineer so I started a Thesis back in 2013 about Water Hammer. Really interesting topic, that needed Finite Differences Methods to solve really complicated Partial Differential Equations. The only proffesor with this knowledge started working wih me, but after a year he got retired. So I had to find another Professor, so in order to avoid this issue to happen again, I decided to go with one of the youngest Professor, well he left me for his Phd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn, Suddenly working in INVAR I noticed the CEO was my professor of Planning so I ask him to mentor me. This happened just before leaving to Aguas del Valle in La Serena. 6 months later a Cancer was diagnosed and he passed away, so freaking fast.
The Chief of Department took over all of the abandoned Thesis that my Professor&amp;rsquo;s dead left behind, but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t continue to mentor me, because he considered being in La Serena was too far away.
In 2015 I came back to Viña and I started to learn, upskill, teach, develop as a Data Scientist that I decided to put it on hold.
On 2017 I started another Thesis. Another Professor wanted to mentor me but he was of the Structural Area. That meant I needed to move to that Area.
We started investigating uncertainty on Structural Analysis. The thing is my work again didn&amp;rsquo;t give me any chance to continue.
Until now. Why now? Probably I will explain it later, because it is also related with the creation of this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-my-thesis-is-going-to-be-about&#34;&gt;What My Thesis is going to be about?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good news, I will be able to mix my previous work with one thing I discovered as I developed as Data Science: &lt;strong&gt;Deep Learning in R&lt;/strong&gt; 👏.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be posting some progress about that. Hang tight!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Project</title>
      <link>/publication/my-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/my-thesis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-am-i-not-graduated-yet&#34;&gt;Why am I not graduated yet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduation is something we all are longing. Well, I recognize this is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been evading. The main reason is because I&amp;rsquo;m not working on what I studied. But, what the hell, I think I like Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, Long Story Short&amp;hellip; I was about to study Mathematical Engineering but I asked myself, where can I possibly work as a Mathematical Engineer ? (In my current job, obviously 😅)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decide to go for Civil Engineering because it has a decent amount of advanced Maths that was something I was looking for and a High Employment Index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I started working as a Civil Engineer in INVAR as soon as I finished my internship. I just loved it, I learned so much, but the thingwas that they didn&amp;rsquo;t pay too much. So I decided to take a position at Aguas del Valle. Sincerely, and very respectfully, it has been the worst choice of my life, not only because it was 5 hours away of my Hometown, but also because they took my soul out of my body and make me spend awful moments doing absolutely nothing. There is nothing more frustrating than doing nothing all day long in a desk in a Company you don&amp;rsquo;t feel a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the Evalueserve Post showed up. A friend referred me to the Data Science Program (DSP) and then I fell in love with Data Science. During the program I learned SQL, VBA, SAS 👍, R, Tableau and definitely built up my English and Communication skills. Felipe, help me prepare my first interview in English and thanks to him I had the English I needed to learn all I know so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upskilling and moving through cities took all of my time, besides I got married (Best Decision so far) but a lot to do, hence, no time to finish my Thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened-with-my-thesis&#34;&gt;What happened with my Thesis?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well in INVAR I worked as an Hidraulics Engineer so I started a Thesis back in 2013 about Water Hammer. Really interesting topic, that needed Finite Differences Methods to solve really complicated Partial Differential Equations. The only proffesor with this knowledge started working wih me, but after a year he got retired. So I had to find another Professor, so in order to avoid this issue to happen again, I decided to go with one of the youngest Professor, well he left me for his Phd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn, Suddenly working in INVAR I noticed the CEO was my professor of Planning so I ask him to mentor me. This happened just before leaving to Aguas del Valle in La Serena. 6 months later a Cancer was diagnosed and he passed away, so freaking fast.
The Chief of Department took over all of the abandoned Thesis that my Professor&amp;rsquo;s dead left behind, but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t continue to mentor me, because he considered being in La Serena was too far away.
In 2015 I came back to Viña and I started to learn, upskill, teach, develop as a Data Scientist that I decided to put it on hold.
On 2017 I started another Thesis. Another Professor wanted to mentor me but he was of the Structural Area. That meant I needed to move to that Area.
We started investigating uncertainty on Structural Analysis. The thing is my work again didn&amp;rsquo;t give me any chance to continue.
Until now. Why now? Probably I will explain it later, because it is also related with the creation of this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-my-thesis-is-going-to-be-about&#34;&gt;What My Thesis is going to be about?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good news, I will be able to mix my previous work with one thing I discovered as I developed as Data Science: &lt;strong&gt;Deep Learning in R&lt;/strong&gt; 👏.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be posting some progress about that. Hang tight!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio</title>
      <link>/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Jupyter Notebooks with Academic</title>
      <link>/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from IPython.core.display import Image
Image(&#39;https://www.python.org/static/community_logos/python-logo-master-v3-TM-flattened.png&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./academic_0_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;print(&amp;quot;Welcome to Academic!&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Welcome to Academic!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-python-and-jupyter&#34;&gt;Install Python and Jupyter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/#download-section&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Anaconda&lt;/a&gt; which includes Python 3 and Jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, for advanced users, install Jupyter notebook with &lt;code&gt;pip3 install jupyter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-new-blog-post-as-usual-https-sourcethemes-com-academic-docs-managing-content-create-a-blog-post&#34;&gt;Create a new blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-a-blog-post&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;as usual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands in your Terminal, substituting &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;my-post&lt;/code&gt; with the file path to your Academic website folder and a name for your blog post (without spaces), respectively:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cd &amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;
hugo new  --kind post post/my-post
cd &amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;/content/post/my-post/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-or-upload-a-jupyter-notebook&#34;&gt;Create or upload a Jupyter notebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following command to start Jupyter within your new blog post folder. Then create a new Jupyter notebook (&lt;em&gt;New &amp;gt; Python Notebook&lt;/em&gt;) or upload a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jupyter notebook
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;convert-notebook-to-markdown&#34;&gt;Convert notebook to Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jupyter nbconvert Untitled.ipynb --to markdown --NbConvertApp.output_files_dir=.

# Copy the contents of Untitled.md and append it to index.md:
cat Untitled.md | tee -a index.md

# Remove the temporary file:
rm Untitled.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;edit-your-post-metadata&#34;&gt;Edit your post metadata&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;index.md&lt;/code&gt; in your text editor and edit the title etc. in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/front-matter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt; according to your preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#featured-image&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;featured image&lt;/a&gt;, place an image named &lt;code&gt;featured&lt;/code&gt; into your post&amp;rsquo;s folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other tips, such as using math, see the guide on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;writing content with Academic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Page</title>
      <link>/tutorial/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;getwd()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;D:/Alfonso/website/content/tutorial&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bla-bla&#34;&gt;bla bla&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon</title>
      <link>/project/my-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/my-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic&lt;/strong&gt; makes it easy to create a beautiful website for free using Markdown. Customize anything on your site with widgets, themes, and language packs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow our easy &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;step by step guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to build your own free website with Academic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the personal demo&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;business demo&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Request a feature or report a bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating? View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support development of Academic:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Donate a coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Become a backer on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/neutreno/works/34387919-academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Decorate your laptop or journal with an Academic sticker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.threadless.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wear the T-shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensible via &lt;strong&gt;color themes&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;widgets/plugins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; for easy formatting and code highlighting, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic network linking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive and mobile friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multilingual and easy to customize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;color-themes&#34;&gt;Color Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.&lt;/p&gt;









  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-1950s.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-1950s_huaf5482f8cea0c5a703a328640e3b7509_21614_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-apogee.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Apogee&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-apogee_hu4b45d99db97150df01464c393bfd17d4_24119_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Coffee theme with Playfair font&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair_hu446a8f670cc5622adcc77b97ba95f6c5_22462_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-cupcake.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cupcake&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-cupcake_hueba8cfa8cfbc7543924fcbf387a99e92_23986_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-dark.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Dark&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-dark_hu1e8601ecc47f58eada7743fdcd709d3d_21456_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-default.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-default_huba6228b7bdf30e2f03f12ea91b2cba0d_21751_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-forest.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Forest&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-forest_hu4f093a1c683134431456584193ea41ee_21797_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-ocean.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ocean&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-ocean_hu14831ccafc2219f30a7a096fa7617e01_21760_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-admin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to import publications from BibTeX or import assets for an offline site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-scripts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Scripts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Scripts to help migrate content to new versions of Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer using Git with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer by downloading the ZIP files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer with RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-install-using-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;Quick install using your web browser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Academic with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netlify will provide you with a customizable URL to access your new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On GitHub, go to your newly created &lt;code&gt;academic-kickstart&lt;/code&gt; repository and edit &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; to personalize your site. Shortly after saving the file, your site will automatically update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-git&#34;&gt;Install with Git&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/#quick-install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart#fork-destination-box&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fork&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt; repository and clone your fork with Git:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart.git My_Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that if you forked Academic Kickstart, the above command should be edited to clone your fork, i.e. replace &lt;code&gt;sourcethemes&lt;/code&gt; with your GitHub username.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialize the theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd My_Website
git submodule update --init --recursive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-zip&#34;&gt;Install with ZIP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract the &lt;em&gt;Academic theme&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/&lt;/code&gt; folder from the above step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-rstudio&#34;&gt;Install with RStudio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the guide to installing Academic with RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you installed on your computer, view your new website by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; and your new Academic powered website will appear. Otherwise, if using Netlify, they will provide you with your URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content, customize your site, and deploy it. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your site by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;host it for free using Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; or Netlify (refer to the first installation method). Alternatively, copy the generated &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, Rsync, etc.) to your production web server (such as a university&amp;rsquo;s hosting service).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of updates and check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; prior to updating your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before updating the framework, it is recommended to make a backup of your entire website directory (or at least your &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; directory) and record your current version number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Academic is installed as a Git submodule which can be updated by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git submodule update --remote --merge
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the update guide&lt;/a&gt; for full instructions and alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-contributing&#34;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; to let me know about any bugs or feature requests, or alternatively make a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Person Re-Identification System For Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/person-re-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/person-re-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
