<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on datacubeR</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on datacubeR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This is just mine. Use it giving proper credit.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 02:08:11 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin R</title>
      <link>/post/latin-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/latin-r/</guid>
      <description>Latin RLatin R is a conference organize by RLadies Latam and is the oportunity we have here to know the last breakthrough and how is being using in Research, companies, etc.They also provide a full day of Tutorials and of course important keynotes are invited to come over. This year I think is huge 3 Main R users are coming:
Mine Çetinkaya-RundelShe is one of the most important persons involved into R Teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Final Project at the ML Diploma (Part I)</title>
      <link>/post/machine-learning-diploma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/machine-learning-diploma/</guid>
      <description>1 Importing Data2 Redefining Categorical Variables3 Discovering Missing Values4 ConclusionDuring my Machine Learning Diploma I had the chance to work on a very interesting project that was actually created in SAS. Of course I absolutely refused to use that old fashioned tool and I move everything to R.
I will try to demonstrate as much of the packages I used to perform this analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Final Project at the ML Diploma (Part II)</title>
      <link>/post/machine-learning-diploma-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/machine-learning-diploma-ii/</guid>
      <description>1 Checking Numerical Distribution2 Checking Categorical Variables3 Chi-Square Test4 ConclusionLast time we conducted a high level cleansing of the data. Now it´s time to understand what is going on in it. In order to do that we´ll use a lot ggplot to visualize the data.
1 Checking Numerical DistributionIn order to do this I should pick Numerical Variables one by one and create a ggplot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Final Project at the ML Diploma (Part III)</title>
      <link>/post/machine-learning-diploma-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/machine-learning-diploma-iii/</guid>
      <description>1 COMING SOON1 COMING SOON</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Well, I got to know Deep Learning by chance. I remember to have had a College subject called Operational Investigation Fundamentals and they taugth Artifical Intelligence algorithms. Neural networks were mentioned but I never thought I could even understand what they were about. During my first real job (as a quasi-Engineer) I always thougth I never paid sufficient attention to that subject. The subject basically covered some optimization models and for some reason AI was there, just sky-high level mentions in some classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Project</title>
      <link>/post/my-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Why am I not graduated yet? Graduation is something we all are longing. Well, I recognize this is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been evading. The main reason is because I&amp;rsquo;m not working on what I studied. But, what the hell, I think I like Data Science.
Ok, Long Story Short&amp;hellip; I was about to study Mathematical Engineering but I asked myself, where can I possibly work as a Mathematical Engineer ? (In my current job, obviously 😅)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>