<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent Posts on datacubeR</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent Posts on datacubeR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> &lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons-by fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons-sa fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;copy;Alfonso Tobar. Made with &lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-r-project&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Blogdown Package.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 02:08:11 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin R (Days 2 and 3)</title>
      <link>/post/latin-r-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/latin-r-ii/</guid>
      <description>Latin R (Conferences Days)Today the Conference Days just got started, and I have to say I watched some really impresive presentations and Data Products.
Day 1 started with a UAI local presenter talking about Sports Analytics in R, then a huge presentation by Mine Cetinkaya about Teaching R to move to specific small presentation in parallel so I was able just to watch half of the Presentations.
Day 2 started with a UC local presenter talking about applying Data Science in R to Government Data, then Erin Ledell talked about H2o to move forward to the small presentations in Parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin R (Day 1)</title>
      <link>/post/latin-r-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/latin-r-i/</guid>
      <description>Latin R (Tutorials Day)Today Latin R just got started. It was really impressive to see how many people actually uses R. I have to say the popularity of Python in Data Science has always been something that worries me tons, but today I was able to see a lot of other Areas where people actually use R. Probably I was one of the few people working in Data Science there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin R</title>
      <link>/post/latin-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/latin-r/</guid>
      <description>Latin RLatin R is a conference organized by RLadies Latam and is the oportunity we have here in Chile to get acquainted about the last R breakthrough and how is being using in Research, companies, etc.They also provide a full day of Tutorials and of course important keynotes are invited to come over. This year I think is huge, because 3 Main R users are coming:
Mine Çetinkaya-RundelShe is one of the most important persons involved into R Teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Well, I got to know Deep Learning by chance. I remember to have had a College subject called Operational Investigation Fundamentals and they taugth Artifical Intelligence algorithms. Neural networks were mentioned but I never thought I could even understand what they were about. During my first real job (as a quasi-Engineer) I always thougth I never paid sufficient attention to that subject. The subject basically covered some optimization models and for some reason AI was there, just sky-high level mentions in some classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Project</title>
      <link>/post/my-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Why am I not graduated yet? Graduation is something we all are longing. Well, I recognize this is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been evading. The main reason is because I&amp;rsquo;m not working on what I studied. But, what the hell, I think I like Data Science.
Ok, Long Story Short&amp;hellip; I was about to study Mathematical Engineering but I asked myself, where can I possibly work as a Mathematical Engineer ? (In my current job, obviously 😅)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>