<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent Posts on datacubeR</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent Posts on datacubeR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> &lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons-by fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons-sa fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;copy;Alfonso Tobar. Made with &lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-r-project&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Blogdown Package.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 04:27:05 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use MLflow</title>
      <link>/post/mlflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mlflow/</guid>
      <description>How to use MLflow I have to say that I love modeling, but at the same time it demands the best of me in terms of being organized. I´m a mess, and that definitely is not helpful when modeling. So I had to put lots of efforts on creating my own folder system that helps me to organize my code, my data and my outputs. But even having all of that there is something I couldn&amp;rsquo;t managed to organize and those are my experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R vs Python, Part II</title>
      <link>/post/r-vs-python-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-vs-python-ii/</guid>
      <description>During last blog post I shared my bad experiences with R in these late days. This doesn’t mean I hate R at all, but it does mean that I’m eagerly learning Python to supply some of the R deficencies.
In this 3 weeks of intensive Python learning I’ve learned a lot and here are some things on why moving to Python.
The main advantage of the Python Data science environment is that you can find everything condesnsed into the Scipy stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R vs Python</title>
      <link>/post/r-vs-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-vs-python/</guid>
      <description>Catching up about meI’ve been working in my new job for the last two months, I’ve had some pros and some cons but that will be another day’s discussion. The reason I’m writing about this is because in my new role I have to create a lot of ML models and sadly, and I really mean sadly, R is not suited for that. And it seems Python is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I got a new job</title>
      <link>/post/new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-job/</guid>
      <description>My new JobMy working relationship with Evalueserve ended the past June and I just dedicated to finish my Thesis. On the first days of October I just started to apply to different Jobs, I have to say my first option was trying to get a Job at H2o, but I´m not there yet.
The thing is that after the first Interview I knew this would be my new Company, I felt some kind of feeling saying “you will work here” (although I had some hesitation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin R (Days 2 and 3)</title>
      <link>/post/latin-r-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/latin-r-ii/</guid>
      <description>Latin R (Conferences Days)Today the Conference Days just got started, and I have to say I watched some really impresive presentations and Data Products.
Day 1 started with a UAI local presenter talking about Sports Analytics in R, then a huge presentation by Mine Cetinkaya about Teaching R to move to specific small presentation in parallel so I was able just to watch half of the Presentations.
Day 2 started with a UC local presenter talking about applying Data Science in R to Government Data, then Erin Ledell talked about H2o to move forward to the small presentations in Parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin R (Day 1)</title>
      <link>/post/latin-r-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/latin-r-i/</guid>
      <description>Latin R (Tutorials Day)Today Latin R just got started. It was really impressive to see how many people actually uses R. I have to say the popularity of Python in Data Science has always been something that worries me tons, but today I was able to see a lot of other Areas where people actually use R. Probably I was one of the few people working in Data Science there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin R</title>
      <link>/post/latin-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/latin-r/</guid>
      <description>Latin RLatin R is a conference organized by RLadies Latam and is the oportunity we have here in Chile to get acquainted about the last R breakthrough and how is being using in Research, companies, etc.They also provide a full day of Tutorials and of course important keynotes are invited to come over. This year I think is huge, because 3 Main R users are coming:
Mine Çetinkaya-RundelShe is one of the most important persons involved into R Teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Well, I got to know Deep Learning by chance. I remember to have had a College subject called Operational Investigation Fundamentals and they taugth Artifical Intelligence algorithms. Neural networks were mentioned but I never thought I could even understand what they were about. During my first real job (as a quasi-Engineer) I always thougth I never paid sufficient attention to that subject. The subject basically covered some optimization models and for some reason AI was there, just sky-high level mentions in some classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Project</title>
      <link>/post/my-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Why am I not graduated yet? Graduation is something we all are longing. Well, I recognize this is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been evading. The main reason is because I&amp;rsquo;m not working on what I studied. But, what the hell, I think I like Data Science.
Ok, Long Story Short&amp;hellip; I was about to study Mathematical Engineering but I asked myself, where can I possibly work as a Mathematical Engineer ? (In my current job, obviously 😅)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>