<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on datacubeR</title>
    <link>/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on datacubeR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This is just mine. Use it giving proper credit.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Propuesta Redes Convolucionales</title>
      <link>/project/convolutional-nets-sp/memoria-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/convolutional-nets-sp/memoria-1/</guid>
      <description>Redes Convolucionales¿Cómo se relaciona esto con las Redes Convolucionales?¿Cómo se va especializando la red para ser cada vez más detallista?¿Cómo se relaciona este problema con Estructuras?El Paper de FinolSoluciónPuntos Interesantes para la Investigación.1era Sugerencia (Quizás no para la Memoria, pero para seguir investigando)2da Sugerencia3era Sugerencia.4ta Sugerencia “Crear Imágenes Estructurales”Redes ConvolucionalesLas redes convolucionales es un tipo de Red que esta especializada principalmente en extraer características de imágenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation Functions</title>
      <link>/project/activation-functions/activation-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/activation-functions/activation-functions/</guid>
      <description>Activation FunctionsIdentityStep FunctionLinear FunctionSigmoid FunctionHyperbolic TangentReLULeaky ReLUSoftmaxHow to choose the perfect Activation function?Activation FunctionsActivation functions are one of the most important characteristic of ANN. They basically decide whether a neuron should be activated or not. When a particular threshold is reached the Neuron will fire, meaning they will transmit the input signal to the next layer of the Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Neural Networks</title>
      <link>/project/neural-nets-101/intro-to-nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/neural-nets-101/intro-to-nn/</guid>
      <description>What is an Artificial Neural Network?Basic StructureWhat Problems can Neural Networks solve?ClassificationRegressionTypical Problems solved with Neural NetworksConclusionWhat is an Artificial Neural Network?The Picture you see up there is far a way from what a real Neural Network looks like:
Actually it is more similar to something like this:
Figure 1: Multi-Layer PerceptronThe configuration showed above is nothing but a visual representation of serial Matrix Multiplications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Well, I got to know Deep Learning by chance. I remember to have had a College subject called Operational Investigation Fundamentals and they taugth Artifical Intelligence algorithms. Neural networks were mentioned but I never thought I could even understand what they were about. During my first real job (as a quasi-Engineer) I always thougth I never paid sufficient attention to that subject. The subject basically covered some optimization models and for some reason AI was there, just sky-high level mentions in some classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>