<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on datacubeR</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on datacubeR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> &lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons-by fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-creative-commons-sa fa-2x&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;copy;Alfonso Tobar. Made with &lt;i class=&#39;fab fa-r-project&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Blogdown Package.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis</title>
      <link>/project/my-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/my-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Coming up with an Interesting Thesis Project is not easy at all. Actually I had 3 different projets and 5 different professors. None of them were really interested in my propositions. Thank God I found Dr. Marcos Valdebenito. He is really interested in Reliability Analysis in Structures and Study the Response of Random Field Variables into Strutures, you can learn more about his work on his website. Once I talked to him about I was doing in my former job he was really interested in applying Machine Learning techniques to solve this kind of problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stiffness Method</title>
      <link>/project/stiffness-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/stiffness-method/</guid>
      <description>The MethodThe ProblemRcpp BasicsCreating an Rcpp fileStiffness MethodStiff Matrix by ElementActive DoF AssemblyConnectivity ArrayStiffness Matrix AssemblyLoad Vector AssemblySolving the ProblemConclusionsThe MethodThe Rayleigh Ritz Method is nothing but applying Finite Elements to Structural problems. Basically you split your structure into smaller structures that can easily be solved By solving, I mean, Calculate the specific stifness of the Structure in order to determine how the loads affects the structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Final Project at the ML Diploma (Part III)</title>
      <link>/project/machine-learning-diploma-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/machine-learning-diploma-iii/</guid>
      <description>1 Tidymodels1.1 Spliting the Data1.2 Pre Processing2 Create the Logistic Regression3 ConclusionsNow we have an idea on how the data looks like it is time to Model.
1 TidymodelsI´m a huge fan of tidymodels framework and the way Max Kuhn has put together all of this system. I´ll be using several packages from this framework in order to show different steps of the Machine Learning Process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Final Project at the ML Diploma (Part II)</title>
      <link>/project/machine-learning-diploma-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/machine-learning-diploma-ii/</guid>
      <description>1 Checking Numerical Distribution2 Checking Categorical Variables3 Chi-Square Test4 ConclusionLast time we conducted a high level cleansing of the data. Now it´s time to understand what is going on in it. In order to do that we´ll use a lot ggplot to visualize the data.
1 Checking Numerical DistributionIn order to do this I should pick Numerical Variables one by one and create a ggplot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Final Project at the ML Diploma (Part I)</title>
      <link>/project/machine-learning-diploma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/machine-learning-diploma/</guid>
      <description>1 Importing Data2 Redefining Categorical Variables3 Discovering Missing Values4 ConclusionDuring my Machine Learning Diploma I had the chance to work on a very interesting project that was actually created in SAS. Of course I absolutely refused to use that old fashioned tool and I move everything to R.
I will try to demonstrate as much of the packages I used to perform this analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propuesta Redes Convolucionales</title>
      <link>/project/convolutional-nets-sp/memoria-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/convolutional-nets-sp/memoria-1/</guid>
      <description>Redes Convolucionales¿Cómo se relaciona esto con las Redes Convolucionales?¿Cómo se va especializando la red para ser cada vez más detallista?¿Cómo se relaciona este problema con Estructuras?El Paper de FinolSoluciónPuntos Interesantes para la Investigación.1era Sugerencia (Quizás no para la Memoria, pero para seguir investigando)2da Sugerencia3era Sugerencia.4ta Sugerencia “Crear Imágenes Estructurales”Redes ConvolucionalesLas redes convolucionales es un tipo de Red que esta especializada principalmente en extraer características de imágenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation Functions</title>
      <link>/project/activation-functions/activation-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/activation-functions/activation-functions/</guid>
      <description>Activation FunctionsIdentityStep FunctionLinear FunctionSigmoid FunctionHyperbolic TangentReLULeaky ReLUSoftmaxHow to choose the perfect Activation function?Activation FunctionsActivation functions are one of the most important characteristic of ANN. They basically decide whether a neuron should be activated or not. When a particular threshold is reached the Neuron will fire, meaning they will transmit the input signal to the next layer of the Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Neural Networks</title>
      <link>/project/neural-nets-101/intro-to-nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/neural-nets-101/intro-to-nn/</guid>
      <description>What is an Artificial Neural Network?Basic StructureWhat Problems can Neural Networks solve?ClassificationRegressionTypical Problems solved with Neural NetworksConclusionWhat is an Artificial Neural Network?The Picture you see up there is far a way from what a real Neural Network looks like:
Actually it is more similar to something like this:
Figure 1: Multi-Layer PerceptronThe configuration showed above is nothing but a visual representation of serial Matrix Multiplications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>